Commuter IC supported here
So hot!
あっつ～！
もう すっかり夏だねえ
Summer's in full swing, huh?
ですね
Very much so!
後藤さんの家
あと少しで着くみたいです
I think we're almost at Gotoh-san's house.
やった～
Great!
Thanks for showing me around, by the way.
っていうか 道案内ありがとね
いえいえ　楽しみですね
Not at all! I'm really
looking forward to this!
うん！　なんか新鮮だよね
Yeah! It'll be such a new experience!
I mean, we mainly only get
together at Starry, right?
ほら あたしたち
STARRY以外で会うこと
ほとんどないしさ
ですね！
Yes!
I wonder what Gotoh-san's house is like!
後藤さんの家って
どんな感じなんでしょうね
ああ 前に 段ボールが狭くて
She said something about a cramped
cardboard box reminding her of home...
家の感じに似てるから落ち着く…
的なことは言ってたな
えっ 段ボールに似てる家って…
A house like a cardboard box?
ぼっちちゃんって
ホント 言うこと面白いよね
Bocchi-chan says the funniest things, huh?
楽しみだな～
I can't wait!
Neither can I!
楽しみですね
私 お菓子とお勧めの映画
持ってきましたよ
I brought some sweets and a movie I like.
Hey! You didn't forget why
we're doing this, did you?
ちょっと　今日の目的 忘れたの？
もちろん覚えてますよ
No, I remember!
ライブで着るＴシャツのデザイン
考えるんですよね？
We're designing T-shirts
for our concert, right?
そう！
Yeah!
リョウ先輩も来ればよかったのに
I wish Ryo-senpai could've come too...
I did invite her, but...
誘ったんだけどね…
ん？
おばあちゃんが
今夜が峠なんだって
She says her grandma
took a turn for the worse.
えっ！　大丈夫なんですか？
Is she all right?!
Oh, she's fine.
大丈夫 大丈夫
This is like the tenth critical time
for her grandma this year.
おばあちゃんの峠
今年で10回目だから
I love the way the guitar comes in here.
今のギターの入り方 いい！
You mean...
それって…
I mean, at least her grandma really exists.
おばあちゃんは
まだ実在してるからいいよ
いや よくないけど
That's a heckuva low bar.
Let's hang out!
Once, when some classmates invited
her to hang out with them...
この前なんて クラスの子に
放課後 遊ぼうって誘われたとき…
Sorry, my dog Pe'z has to have surgery.
ごめん
sob sob sob
愛犬のぺスが
手術することになって
えっ！
What?!
So she said, but she's never even had a dog.
って！　犬なんて
一度も飼ったことないのに
飼ってないんですか？
She hasn't?
She hasn't!
そうだよ
Then there's "I just got a call from
my twin sister separated at birth,"
ほかにも 生き別れの双子の妹から
連絡が来たとか
お父さんが事故で
記憶喪失になったとか
and "my dad was in a car crash,
and now he has amnesia."
しょうもない言い訳を…
Just all the silliest excuses...
I'm impressed by how easily she comes up
with such a wide range of lies.
そんなスラスラと
バラエティ豊富なウソが
思いつくなんて
Senpai's amazing!
さすが先輩　悪女で すてき！
I love me a bad girl!
That's a serious Ryo obsession right there.
リョウ狂いも ここまでくると…
あっ
ん？
着きました！　ここです
We're here! This is it!
ん～？
Welcome!  Members of Kessoku Band
We Hope Your Time Here Heals You in Both Mind and Body
えっ？
ここ… だよね？
This... is it, isn't it?
It... does say "Kessoku Band," right?
“結束バンド”って
書いてあるもんね
後藤さんの家って
Did she mention her house was a ryokan?
旅館でしたっけ？
I'm not sure. It just looks like
a normal house to me.
知らないけど
どっからどう見ても
普通の一軒家だね
ですね
Yeah.
とりあえず！
Anyway...
ハッ！
ぼっちちゃん 来たよ～
We're here, Bocchi-chan!
Hello!
こんにちは～
あっ ああ
いいい… 今 開けま～す！
C-Coming!
Sergeant For a Day
Y-Yaaaay!
イ… イエ～イ！
ウェ ウェウェ… ウェルカ～ム！
W-W-Welcome!
I liked dark, cramped spaces,
so I'd bury my face deep in my hood
My eyes resented the heartless world,
but yearned for love
I liked being soaked by the rain,
because my face looked better clouded over
I pretended to be afraid of the storm
while waiting for the sky to burst
Strum through the light's distortion
I want to make thunder roar
Drum beyond the pain
What can I do? This fierce
pounding is out of control
Strum in a harmonizing quartet
I want to cause a revolution
Drum in a lamenting forte
What can I do? My savage
nature is beyond wild
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#07 To Your House
Sergeant For a Day
Are you having fun, Bocchi-chan?
ぼっちちゃん 楽しそうだね
Y-Yeah...
あっ はい…
I b-b-bombed...
スス… スベった！
Isn't that nice?
なんだか うれしいですね！
Gotoh-san's made it clear how much
she's been looking forward to this too!
後藤さんも 今日
楽しみにしてくれてたって分かって
Kita-san knows the kindest words
to soothe my bombed soul.
喜多さんの優しさが
スベった心にしみる！
C-Come in.
ど… どうぞ
Okay!
Welcome!  Members of Kessoku Band
We Hope Your Time Here Heals You in Both Mind and Body
は～い
Coming in!
おじゃまします～
Gotoh-san, these are for you.
後藤さん これ お土産
Please enjoy them with your family.
ご家族で召し上がってね
Wh-What?
あっ えっ？
あ… ありがとうございます
Th-Thank you...
Ah, t-trendiness emanates from the bag!
うわあ～ 紙袋から
shining
Trendy
smells so good
お… おしゃれな何かが
あふれ出てる！
I brought a movie, too!
映画もありますよ
I told you, we have to figure out
our T-shirt design for the concert!
だから～
ライブのＴシャツデザイン
考えるんでしょ
Rather than just wearing whatever,
バラバラの服より
おそろいのほうが
wouldn't having matching outfits
一体感？　バンド感？
create a sense of one-ness?
A sense of band-ness?!
Am I wrong here?
Ripe Mangos
そういうの出るんじゃない？
それに…
Besides...
There's nothing tying you guys together.
全然 結束感ねえな
とか 絶対言われるし！
うん うん
I know that's what she'll say!
You get it? We're not here to play around!
分かった？
こ… こっちです
Th-This way...
遊びに来たんじゃないんだからね
んっ… ん～？
Welcome to Chez Gotoh
I-I'm sorry. I'll put it all away.
す… すみません
全部 片づけますね
W-Well, we could play around a little!
ああっ
やっぱり ちょっとは遊ぼうかな！
Yes, I'd love that!
はい 賛成です！
じゃ… じゃあ
飲み物 取ってきます
W-Well then, I'll fetch the drinks.
楽にしててください
Please make yourselves at home.
Thanks!
ありがとう！
フウ～
But wow, she really went
all-out with the decorations!
それにしても すごい飾りつけだね
There's nothing here besides the guitar
and effects unit, though.
でも ギターとか
エフェクター 何もありませんね
だね
Yeah...
I just assumed her room would have
a bit more of a rock feel to—
私 勝手に もう少し
ロックな感じの
部屋してるのかと思って…
Sealed
Is this... rock?
これは ロック？
Yeah, it's pretty rock!
うん… ロックしてるね
ほ… ほかには
ロックなところ あるかな～
I w-wonder if there's
anything else rock about i—
イタッ
Ow!
あっ
あれ？
Huh? Why does she have so
many copies of our ProPho?
なんで こんなに
アー写がたくさん？
ううっ？
Sealed Sealed Sealed
ひゃあ！
ううっ 分からないけど
I don't know what's going on,
but it seems pretty darn rock!
なんか
めちゃめちゃロックな気がする…
うう～
She's got blown-up ones too!
でっかいのもあるよ
ひっ… ひい～っ！
Welcome to Chez Gotoh
She had this picture stuck up
all over her room.
この写真
部屋に い～っぱい貼ってたんだよ
She said she really liked it!
すっごく気に入った写真なんだって
え？
But Mom told her to take them down
because they were hurting her eyes.
でも お母さんに
目がチカチカするから
はがしなさいって止められたの
And we put those seals up
when Sis was possessed before!
あと そっちの お札とかは
お姉ちゃんが この前
お化けに取りつかれたから
貼ってあるんだ
以上 説明おしまい！
That should just about cover it!
ワン ワン！
もしかして 後藤さんの妹？
Wait, are you Gotoh-san's sister?
はい！
はじめまして 後藤ふたりです
Yes! A pleasure to meet you.
I'm Futari Gotoh.
犬はジミヘン
The dog's Jimihen.
クウ～ン
ああ…
む… 麦茶でよかったのかな
I hope barley tea's okay.
もっと
おしゃれな飲み物のほうが…
Or would they prefer a trendier drink?
かわいい～！
え？
So cute!
あっ 皆さん お待たせしまし…
Sorry to keep you guys wa—
ねえ
ギターで むによんずの歌 弾いて
Hey, will you play the
Munions song on guitar?
じゃあ 今度来るときまでに
練習しとくね
I'll practice so I can do it
the next time I come by.
絶対だよ！　次 いつ来る？
You gotta! When's the next time you come by?
I-Is this...
こ… これは…
アハッ ジミヘンは人懐っこいね
Jimihen's a friendly little guy!
Th-They're getting along so well,
there's no room left for me...
すっ すす… すっかり打ち解けて
わわ… 私の入る隙がない
あれ ぼっちちゃん？
Huh? Bocchi-chan?
後藤さん？
Gotoh-san?
５歳児と犬以下のコミュ力…
A five-year-old and a dog
have better social skills than me.
あっ お姉ちゃん また固まってる
Sis is frozen up again.
ふ… ふたり
ななな… なんで ここにいるの？
F-Futari. Wh-What are you doing here?
お母さんたちは？
Wh-Where are Mom and Dad?
お買い物
Shopping.
お… お姉ちゃん
今から大事な お話するから
I-I-I've got grown-up things to talk about,
so please go play with Jimihen.
ジミヘンと遊んでてね
えっ つまんない～！
Aw, no fun!
私は別に
ふたりちゃんがいても大丈夫よ
I don't mind having Futari-chan here.
Yeah, same!
うん あたしも
ダダダダダ… ダメです
Y-Y-Y-You can't!
I c-c-can't whoop it up if my sister's here!
い… 妹いたら
は… はっちゃけられないので！
ぼっちちゃん
Bocchi-chan, you've been
whooping it up with us all this time?
あたしらの前で
はっちゃけてたんだ
I beg of you!
お願いします！
Please go play with Jimihen!
ジミヘンと遊んでいてください！
ええ～っ
You can have an ice pop from the freezer.
冷凍庫のアイス 食べていいから
ハッ…
もう しょうがないなあ～
Well, it is what it is!
ワン ワン ワン！
You've got such a sisterly bond!
姉妹 仲良しなのね　ウフフッ
How did you get that
from what just happened?
えっ？　今のやりとりの
どこで それ感じた？
それじゃ
Ｔシャツのデザイン 決めよう！
Now, let's design those T-shirts!
Let's Draw
Feel free to use these!
みんなは これに自由に描いて
は～い
はい…
Okay!
Okay...
We could just slap
our logo on there,
無難に ロゴＴでもいいんだけど
そのままグッズにして
物販で売りたいと思ってるし
but I'd love to sell the shirts as merch, too!
に… 虹夏ちゃん 物販に貪欲
N-Nijika-chan is so hungry for merch!
みんなから それ以上に
いい案が出たら採用しますので
So if you have any other great ideas,
I might use those as well!
よ～し
後藤さん 頑張りましょう
Okay! Let's do our best, Gotoh-san!
は… はい
R-Right!
たまには
みんなに いいとこ見せないと！
I have to impress the others for once!
C'mon, take that stuff off
before you try to look serious!
その格好で
真面目な顔するのやめて～
What? They really came?
えっ ホントに遊びに来てる？
ホントのホントに？
Really? For real?
ワン
うん
Yeah!
お姉ちゃんの妄想じゃなくて？
These friends aren't just the imaginary kind?
ワンワン
うんうん
Yeah, yeah!
Welcome to Chez Gotoh
フフッ 出来ました！
All done!
Let me see!
おっ どんなの どんなの？
Win it
Go for it!
Kessoku
Band
Together,
let's seize
the flower
of victory!
The concept is friendship,
effort, and victory!
コンセプトは
友情 努力 勝利で～す
体育祭で見るやつ！
It's not a dang sports festival!
ええ～？
Aw, but I think it's cute!
かわいくないですか？
待って　優勝って何？
Hang on. What are we winning at?
I'm not sure how "victory"
applies to a concert...
ライブに そんな概念ないけど
んっと～ ノリです
Um... vibes!
Vibes?
ノリ？
I just think wearing these would
really get us feeling like a unit!
だって こういうの着たら
みんなの心が
ひとつになる気がしません？
ねえ？　後藤さ…
Right, Gotoh-sa—
あっ
ク… クラス 一致団結！
C-Class unity...
ぼっちちゃん
体育祭に相当なトラウマが？
Bocchi-chan!
Is the idea of a sports festival
that traumatic for you?!
Sports Festival
体育祭 それは…
The sports festival:
the number one-source of
school trauma for introverts.
School Trauma Sources for Introverts
1st Place
Parentheses, based on Japanese Introvert
Society poll, close parentheses.
(Based on Japanese Introvert Society Poll)
A heinous ritual in which those
with no athletic ability are shunned,
運動のできない者は煙たがられ
存在価値を奪われる
忌まわしき祭典！
and even their right to exist
is stripped away.
Not only during school hours,
but afterward too,
授業内だけでなく放課後も
横断幕制作や応援練習に
駆り出される強制労働！
they are forced to perform slave labor,
creating banners and practicing cheers!
One for all! All for one!
ひとりは みんなのために！
みんなは ひとりのために！
Class Unity
うわあ～！
One for all! All for one!
ひとりは みんなのために！
約１か月
An entire month's torturous existence
living for naught but the sports festival!
体育祭のためだけに生きることを
強いられる拷問行為！
One for all! All for one!
Class Unity
みんなは ひとりのために！
Welcome to Chez Gotoh
あああ…
Looks like Gotoh-san melted.
後藤さん 溶けちゃいましたね
It sure is hot today!
今日 暑いからね～
This way to
School Festival
NO 協調性　NO ライフ…
No cooperation, no life!
But the true terror lurking
behind every sports festival...
体育祭…
このイベントの真に怖いところは！
NO 協調性　NO ライフ！
NO 協調性　NO ライフ…
ああ…
Wow, this week's Bocchi Time lasted
through the whole commercial break!
今日の ぼっちタイム
ＣＭまたぐぐらい長いね
Did I do something wrong?
私 なんかしちゃいました？
まったく
罪な女だね 喜多ちゃんは
You've really put your foot
in it now, Kita-chan!
What? Come back, Gotoh-san!
ええっ？
後藤さん 戻ってきて！
No cooperation, no life!
A place in which introverts
are constantly underfoot,
結局 陰キャが
何をしても邪魔な存在であり
but if they just sit quietly in a corner,
隅のほうで じっとしていても
非協力的と罵られるところである！
they're persecuted for
not being team players!
Death to those who bring down
the sports festival mood!
“体育祭を
盛り下げたで賞”で死刑！
わあああ～っ！
No cooperation, no life!
NO 協調性　NO ライフ！
See? They really exist!
ほら　本当に いるでしょ？
わっ
あっ
Hello!
こんにちは
おじゃましてます
Thanks for having us!
Isn't it wonderful?
いや～ 感動だなあ
ひとりのお友達が遊びに来る日が
来るなんて
I never imagined Hitori
would have real friends over!
Eat your fill, all right?
たくさん食べてね
はい
ありがとうございます
Sure!
Thanks so much!
ひとりと
バンド組んでくれてるんだよね？
You let Hitori join your band, right?
はい
Yes.
We didn't exactly "let" her join.
くれてるっていうか
あたしがお願いして
I asked her to join, and she
was willing to humor me.
メンバーに なってもらった
っていうか…
へえ～ そうなんだ
Really?
See? Music really brings people together!
ほらな？
音楽は人と人をつなぐんだよ
Right, Jimihen?
な？　ジミヘン
ワン ワン！
この子 自分の世界に入って
She doesn't cause too much trouble with her
retreats into her own little world, does she?
迷惑とか かけてない？
Aw, that's no trouble at all!
ああ… でも 全然 迷惑だなんて
Yeah! It's fun!
フフッ そうそう！　面白いよね
そうなんだ
Nice to hear.
はい 出来たよ
うん
Here, it's done.
いつまでも
体育祭を引きずってるところが
The fact that I'm still
upset about school festivals
更に自分が陰キャなのを自覚させ
つらくなる
makes me realize I'm a downer even more,
which made everything worse...
から揚げ 揚げたてです～
Karaage's done!
あっ…
わあ～ おいしそう！
Wow, that looks good!
奥がニンニクしょうゆで
手前が塩こうじ
That one is soy sauce with garlic,
and this one is shio koji.
お好みでレモンと七味をどうぞ
And there's lemon and
shichimi spice to taste.
Thanks!
いただきます！
Kita-chan, eat!
喜多ちゃん 食べよ～
は～い
Okay!
わあ…
友達が来るって聞いたとき
When she said she had friends coming,
I assumed they were imaginary
or hallucinations,
多分 妄想か幻想だろう
って思ったけど
一応 写真もあるし
but then, she did have that picture...
幻想って…
Hallucinations?
But of course, image editing software
is pretty sophisticated these days...
でもね 今は画像くらい
いくらでも加工できるし
Software?
加工？
一応 聞くけど
If I might ask, you're not from
some kind of friend rental servi—
レンタル友達的な
サービスの人じゃ…
正真正銘のバンド仲間です！
We're her bona fide bandmates!
そっか そっか
Oh, okay.
I can't say it doesn't sound
like something I'd do...
It's just that Hitori's never
brought a friend home before.
確かに 私なら やりかねないけど
お父さん お母さんの
私のイメージって…
but hearing Mom and Dad's
ideas about me is so...
So Bocchi's like this even at home.
ぼっちちゃん
家でも こういうキャラなんだ
この子 何日か前から
ずっとソワソワしてたのよ
She's been so restless for days now.
She said something about practicing
decorating her room,
お部屋の飾りつけの
練習だとかいって
put it all up, took it all down,
and put it back up, over and over again.
飾りつけては片づけ
飾りつけては片づけを繰り返してて
And she played a simulated game of Twister,
just in case you played.
あと やるかもしれないからって
ツイスターの
イメージトレーニングだっけ？
M-Mom! Dad!
お… お母さん お父さん
そ… そういうこと
ペラペラしゃべらないで
You don't have to tell them all that stuff!
I'm glad we went shopping just in case!
念のため
お買い物行って よかったね
Okay, this is a day worth remembering!
よ～し 今日を
我が家の記念日にしよう
A friend-a-versary!
友達記念日！
記念日 記念日～
Friend-a-versity!
ワン ワワワン！
C-Cut it out already!
や… やめてよ もう
あっ そうだ
That's right.
The job she said she'd gotten...
あの子が
バイトを始めたっていうのは…
私の姉のライブハウスです
Yeah, it's at my sister's club.
ぼっちちゃんは基本
ドリンクの接客を
Bocchi-chan mainly serves
drinks to customers.
T-To customers?!
せ… 接客？
Yeah!
It does feel pretty weird to
have friends at my house...
自分の家に友達がいるのって
Am I dreaming?
なんだか不思議だな
Amazing. Music really does
cause personal growth!
音楽が
ここまで人を成長させるとは
あっ いきなり親が乱入してきて
And you were having so much fun
when we burst in like that!
若者同士で楽しみたいよね
ごめんなさい
I'm so sorry.
Maybe we should butt out?
Welcome!  Members of Kessoku Band
We Hope Your Time Here Heals You in Both Mind and Body
えっ？
ん～？
Hey, hey, Kita-chan!
ねえねえ 喜多ちゃん
これ なあに？
What's this?
That's my favorite heartwarming movie!
それね すごくキュンとして
お勧めなの！
I've always wanted to watch that one!
それ 実は
あたしも見たかったんだよね
Wanna watch it all together?
じゃあ みんなで見ちゃう？
さんせ～い！
ワン ワン～！
Yes, please!
Great idea! What fun!
いいね いいね！
なんか楽しいね！
フフフッ
イエ～イ！
Yeah! So fun! So fun! Yeah!
Alienation
I don't know why, but... it feels
kind of hard to go back in now...
あれ？　なんだろ…
楽しい！　楽しい！
Alienation
いつの間にか
戻りにくい空気になってる
Alienation
イエ～イ！
Welcome!  Members of Kessoku Band
We Hope Your Time Here Heals You in Both Mind and Body
The large Typhoon #8 remains on the move,
Typhoon #8
(As of 9th, 4 pm)
Size: _
Power: Strong
Dir/Spd: East 120 km/h
Pressure at Eye: 970 hPa
Max. Wind Speed: 35 m/s
Max. Gusts: 50 m/s
Upcoming Weather: Typhoon #8 Passes South of Japan
発達を続けていた
大型の台風８号は
and will lose strength while
passing to the south of Japan...
今後 勢力を落としながら
日本の南海上を
通過していくと予想され…
With new house rules!
More exciting than ever!
Thinking of You
Kisses Over Flowers
At parties!
With family! As couples!
We ended up watching the movie,
playing games, and having nothing but fun.
結局 映画見て ゲームして
遊び倒してしまった
Twister and Tycoon were so much fun to play!
ツイスターと
大富豪 楽しかったですね
Yeah! So much fun!
楽しかったよ！
すごく楽しかった！
And yet...
けども…
That's right! We still need to design
our T-shirts for the concert.
ですね
ライブＴのデザイン
考えないとですね！
Oh, wait...
って あれ？
Senpai! Gotoh-san's back to it!
先輩 また後藤さんが！
ああ これは あれだね
Oh, I know why.
Watching that heartwarming seishun movie
has her back in a spiral.
青春胸キュン映画を見て
また 食らっちゃったんだね
青春胸キュン映画
また私やっちゃいました？
Heartwarming
Seishun Movie
Heartwarming seishun movies:
I did it again?!
それは…
the number-one source of movie
trauma for introverts, by genre.
Traumatic Movie Genres for Introverts
1st Place
(Based on Japanese Introvert Society Poll)
Parentheses, based on Japanese
Introvert Society poll, close—
Bocchi-chan! We're running
out of time! Snap out of it!
ぼっちちゃん
もう時間ないから 頑張って
へ… 平凡女子がイケメン…
A-An ordinary girl has two hot
guys trying to win her heart...
Gotoh-san!
後藤さ～ん
It's hopeless.
But if someone that cute is "ordinary,"
what hope is there for me?
ダメだ こりゃ
あっ
おっ リョウからも
たくさん デザイン案が届いたよ
Ryo sent in a bunch of design ideas!
えっ 見たいです！
見せてください！
Let me see! I want to see!
C'mon! Look with us, Bocchi-chan!
ほら 一緒に見ようよ ぼっちちゃん
ん？
Wh-What in the world?
な… 何これ？
Curry?
カレー？
ん？
Now sushi...
今度は おすしです
I don't get it.
意味分かんないんだけど
Which should I have for dinner?
晩飯
どっちがいいかな？
ぐっ…
はあ～！
Fried Rice
Ramen Set
自分で考えろ！
Make your own decisions!
フッ…
"I think curry's better!"
“カレーがいいです”っと
Kita-chan, don't actually respond!
喜多ちゃんも真面目に返さない！
E-Excuse me...
あ… あの！
ん？
Hey, Bocchi-chan's back?
おっ ぼっちちゃん 復活？
Y-Yes...
あっ はい
I thought you might like to see my design...
私のデザインも
見てくださればと…
Let's Draw
あ…
ハッ！
What do you think?
どうでしょう？
ダ… ダセえ～！
S-So lame!
I-Is it too trendy?
お… おしゃれすぎますかね？
It's that mystery font I see on middle
school boys' clothing all the time.
中学生男子の服に よくある
謎フォントだわ
I thought it would keep people focused
on our clothing when we're playing.
これだとライブ中
服のほうに
目が行っちゃいますよね
Yeah, for several reasons.
うん いろんな意味で
What's the point of all
the zippers and chains?
その大量の
ファスナーと鎖は何に使うの？
I thought I could use
the zippers to hold picks,
あっ ファスナーはピック入れで
and the chain could serve
as a guitar strap.
鎖はギターストラップにもなります
Weirdly practical!
意外と実用的！
エヘヘヘヘ…
So, can I assume we're all in on this one?
じゃ これが採用ということで
よろしいでしょうか？
I'm not sure about that...
それは どうでしょう？
Is this what you like to wear normally?
もしかして
私服も こんな感じかな？
あっ 服は
お母さんが買ってきてくれるから
My mom buys my clothes, so no.
違います
Oh, really?
ああ そうなの？
I've never worn any of them, though...
一度も着たことないけど
They're not to my taste.
好みじゃないから…
Aw, I wanna see!
ええ～ 見てみたい！
私もジャージ以外の後藤さん
見たことないです
Same! I've never seen you in
anything but the tracksuit!
C'mon, please! Try one on!
ねえ お願い！
ちょっと着てみて～
えっ？
お願い お願い！
Please! Please!
ええ～っ
お願い お願い
お願い お願い お願い お願い！
Please! Please! Please!
F-Fine...
いっ いいですけど…
やった～！
Yeah!
うっ これは…
She's so...
C-Cute!
か… かわいい～！
I love it! Look right this way!
すてき！　こっち向いて！
あっ いや 写真は…
N-No pictures, please...
I knew it! Bocchi-chan's cute!
そうだよ
ぼっちちゃんは かわいいんだよ
It's easy to forget, with how she usually is!
ふだんの奇行で
忘れるところでしたね！
あっ あの… もう脱いでも？
U-Um... c-can I take it off now?
待って 待って
Wait, hang on!
I know!
そうだ 前髪も上げなよ！
Let's brush back your bangs!
絶対 そっちのほうがいいって
That's what you need!
えっ…
Are you growing them out?
伸ばしてるの？
あっ 美容室 行けないから
I j-just can't get to the salon,
so they grow out...
伸びているだけで…
なら あたしがセットしてあげよう
Then I'll do some styling!
あっ いや 大丈夫です
N-No, thank you!
遠慮せず～
Aw, don't be shy!
うっ！
ハッ…
Bocchi-chan's turning to ash!
ぼっちちゃんが
どんどん しおれていく！
Her body can't keep up with the sudden
stress of her face being exposed!
顔を さらされたことへの
急激なストレスに
体が ついていけなかったんだわ！
うう…
Bocchi-chan's... dead.
ぼっちちゃん 死んじゃった…
新しいギタリスト
探さないとですね
We'll have to find a new guitarist.
ぐうっ！
あっ 先輩 どうしました？
Senpai! What's wrong?
I'm suddenly so dizzy...
急に めまいが…
えっ？
な… なんか急に
この部屋 ジメジメしてきて
The room is so damp all of a sudden,
like all the air's been sucked out of it...
酸素 薄くなったみたいな…
うっ… 肺に入った！
I breathed it in!
S-So did I!
あっ やだ 私も
うぐっ ダメだ…
力が抜けていく…
I-It's no use. G-Going limp...
Is this... Gotoh-san's curse?
後藤さんの呪い… だわ…
みんな デザート食べない？
Would anyone like dessert?
We've got the sweets Kita-chan brought—
喜多ちゃんが
持ってきてくれたスイーツを…
ええ～っ！
いつも明るさだけで
乗り越えようとして すみません
I'm sorry for trying to push
through everything with positivity.
I'm sorry I couldn't get good at guitar.
ギター うまくならなくて
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry for being too cute.
かわいすぎて ごめんなさい
アハハハッ
みんな お姉ちゃんみたい
They're all acting like Sis!
ワン ワン！
あっ お父さん 塩とお札！
Dear, the salt and the seals!
れ… 霊媒師さん呼ぶ？
Should I call that exorcist?
Nijika
You'll have to do the concert yourself.
Why?
なんでだよ
Several Days Later
And so...
そんなわけで
いい案が出なかったので
Since nobody had any good ideas,
Ｔシャツは
あたしの案になりました
we're going with my T-shirt design!
Ta-dah.
じゃじゃ～ん
Kessoku Band
I love it!
すてき！
これ 伊地知先輩が
作ったんですか？
Did you make this, Ijichi-senpai?!
あたし デザインとか得意なのだ
I'm pretty good at the design stuff!
Then why didn't you just
design it from the start?
なら 最初から
虹夏ちゃんがデザインすれば
よかったのでは？
ぼっちちゃん
Bocchi-chan.
ん？
You look like you were just thinking,
"Then why didn't you just design it from the start?"
なら 最初から
虹夏ちゃんがデザインすれば
よかったのでは？
とでも言いたげな目だね
エ… エスパー！
Sh-She's psychic!
はわわわ…
Let's Draw
フッ フフ～ン
I'm getting pretty good at
guessing what you're thinking lately!
ぼっちちゃんの考えてること
だんだんと
分かるようになってきたかも～！
Awesome! Our ties feel so much stronger now!
いいね～　出てるよ 結束感！
うん すごくいいですよ これ！
Yeah, I love it!
The quality of the model helps.
Kessoku Band
あと モデルがいいから
ですよね～
先輩 目線こっちで～す！
Totally!
Senpai, look right here!
This is pretty good, though.
これは これでいいかも
Two days to our concert.
あさってはライブ
And we worked hard to make our ties feel...
４人で頑張ってきた結果が
ついに…
Hey, looks like there's a typhoon on the way.
なんか今 台風来てるみたいですよ
ええ～っ！
ウソでしょ？
No way! This is the first I've heard of it!
そんなの出てなかったよ！
Summer weather is so fickle.
夏の天気は気まぐれ
マジか～
Seriously?
B-But what about the concert?
じゃ… じゃあ ライブは？
あっ
Should we make rain charms?
てるてる坊主 作る？
Yeah! That's our only choice!
それだ！　作るしかない
１人 ノルマ10個！
Your quota is ten each!
は… はい！
R-Right!
Oh, it looks like it won't
hit the Kanto region, though.
あっ でも
関東には当たらないみたいです
Oh, really?
えっ そうなの？
Whew, that's a relief!
な～んだ よかった～
I can't wait for the show!
本番 楽しみですね
うん
Yeah.
I think the new song's coming
together pretty well!
新曲
結構いい感じになってきたよね
U-Um...
あっ あの…
ですよね！
Yeah! We're all sounding awesome!
みんな かっこいいです
Okay, let's get practicing!
よ～し　じゃあ 練習始めようか
Excuse me!
あの！
ん？
ねねね… 念のために
つ… 作りませんか？
Sh-Shouldn't we still make the
rain charms? Just to be safe?
てるてる坊主！
あっ
そうだね　念には念を
Yeah, sure! Better safe than sorry, right?
Totally!
ですね
I'll bring in what we need to make them.
あたし 道具持ってくるよ
は… はい！
O-Okay!
I haven't made rain charms
since elementary school!
てるてる坊主作るの小学生ぶり…
私がネガティブだから
I'm used to being negative,
so I always assume the worst, but...
Sorry, the five younger brothers
I haven't seen since birth—
良くない方向に考えちゃうけど
Stop acting above it! It was your idea!
You okay, Bocchi-chan?
ぼっちちゃん 大丈夫？
あっ
Y-Y-Y-Y-Yes!
Kessoku Band
ははは… はい！
It'll be okay... I think.
大丈夫… だよね？
Course Changed to Make Landfall
Look Out for Strong Winds and Heavy Rain
Typhoon #8
(As of 14th, 8 am)
Size: _
Power: Intense
Dir/Spd: Northeast 180 km/h
Pressure at Eye: 930 hPa
Max. Wind Speed: 60 m/s
Max. Gusts: 85 m/s
Typhoon #8 has taken an unexpected course...
台風８号は
予想外の進路を取っており…
え…
DAY OF THE CONCERT
I sleep, with big problems
weighing down on me
Though you can't beat that feeling
of being loved, it's true
When I awaken from cold dreams,
my body feels numb
You shine so brightly,
it could make me a shadow
It's time to take that step
Though there's nothing certain about it
It carries my childish heart into tomorrow
It's time to blast out the thoughts
rattling around in my brain
And live, to its fullest, a life
I've been taking advances on for so long
But I also love the days I spend
lying around, doing nothing
So I know I'm going to go see you
Before it all disappears some day
#08 Bocchi the Rock
Watch it!
見てください